http://bestpractical.com/privacy-policy

My Account
Privacy Policy for Best Practical WebsitesThis states the Privacy Policy applicable to the bestpractical.com, forum.bestpractical.com , issues.bestpractical.com, and wiki.bestpractical.com (aka rt-wiki.bestpractical.com) websites (each a “Website,” collectively “the Websites” or “these Websites”) as of June 7, 2018. Please review this document carefully. As used herein, the words “user,” “you,” and “your” mean users of or visitors to the Websites. The words “we,” “our,” “the Company,” “BPS,” and “Best Practical” mean Best Practical Solutions, LLC, the owner and operator of the websites. This Privacy Policy specifically pertains to using these Websites and does not apply to our Products (Request Tracker aka RT and Request Tracker for Incident Response aka RTIR.) Because our Products are Open Source and licensed under GNU General Public License, each instance is governed by the organization which operates, administers, and/or hosts it. This Privacy Policy also does not include any third party services for which a separate privacy policy is applicable.Sections:- Section 1: Collection and use of non-personal information- Section 2: Use of cookies- Section 3: Collection of personal information- Section 4: Use, retention, and security of personal information- Section 5: Links to other sites- Section 6: Opting out- Section 7: Additional legal disclosures- Section 8: ContactSection 1: Collection and Use of Non-personal InformationIf you visit these Websites, we do not collect any personally identifiable information about you (such as your name, address, phone number, or email address) unless you provide it, either directly or through a third party, as described under “Collection of personal information” below. We do, however, collect non-personally-identifiable (anonymous) information about you from your use of the site.This non-personally-identifiable information includes: IP addresses, preferences, web pages you visited prior to coming to our site, information about your browser, network or device (such as browser type and version, operating system, internet service provider, preference settings, unique device IDs, language, and other regional settings), information about how you interact with our site (such as timestamps, clicks, scrolling, browsing times, searches, transactions, referral pages, load times, and problems you may encounter, such as loading errors.)We collect data from the web logs of our servers- the computers that "serve up" web pages- delivering content on the Websites. This includes information about what you view and, along with information gathered from our other users, we create "aggregate data" reports that we may disclose to third parties. We may also study aggregate data in order to enhance our existing services or develop new services. We will not disclose any personal information to a third party without your express prior written authorization, as described under “Use, retention, and security of personal information” below. We can and will use IP addresses to identify a user when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our or terms of use or to protect our service, site, customers, or others.Section 2: Use of Cookies We use cookies, which are small text files placed on your computer's hard drive, and web beacons (also known as pixel tags), which are electronic images embedded into a web page, on the Websites. Cookies and web beacons are used for record keeping, to track your movements when you visit the Websites and to help us determine what type of information to present to you. The use of cookies and web beacons is an industry standard - you'll find them used at most websites. Our cookies and web beacons do not contain any personally identifiable information about you, and do not damage or alter your system files in any way. The first time you visit the Websites, BPS assigns you a unique, anonymous, ID, which is stored in the cookie on your computer.Section 3: Collection of Personal InformationAll personally identifying information we collect is acquired one of two ways: you provide it directly (such as filling out forms requesting information or services, posting to the forum, commenting on the BPS blog), or, we receive some of it through third parties (such as when you make payments to us using our payment processor.) This may include things like email address, name, company, phone number, etc.Your information is being collected solely by BPS. We do not sell, share, trade, or rent your personal information to anyone, other than to persons who help us provide our products and services to you or to comply with law.Please note any content you add or any change you make to the wiki, or forum, or any comments you add to the Best Practical blog, may be publicly and permanently available. Use of the forum, wiki, or blog is at your own risk and discretion.Section 4: Use, Retention, and Security of Personal InformationAll personally identifying information is used in one or more of the following ways:- To communicate with you.- To provide BPS products and services.- To personalize marketing.- To process payments.Any manner in which we may use any personally identifiable information other than those listed in this Privacy Policy will be disclosed when you provide the information and we will request your express consent to such use.We retain non-personally identifiable information collected from web site visitors indefinitely.  We retain your personally identifiable information only as long as necessary for the purpose for which you provide it or as required by law.We maintain and process all information within the United States.Best Practical has implemented generally accepted standards of technology security in order to protect information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Only employees of BPS have access to the information we collect, and these employees are made aware of and required to comply with our Privacy Policy.If you are located in the European Union, any personally identifiable information you provide us will be collected, used and retained in accordance with EU Directive 95/46/EC, EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 and the EU – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States.Section 5: Links to Other SitesThe Websites may provide links to an external website. When you click on such a link, you will leave the Websites. The privacy policy of the external website will then be in effect, not our policy. We do not control or make an endorsement of any kind regarding the external site or its privacy policy. Our policy does not extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet, and therefore beyond our control, and is not to be applied in any manner contrary to applicable law or governmental regulation. We do not control cookies from the other sites that you may link to from the Websites.Section 6: Opting OutTo have your information removed from our contact lists or to amend or modify any of your information, please send an email to contact@bestpractical.com. Alternately, if you have signed up for any of our newsletters, there is an unsubscribe link at the bottom of each message. Please note that if you initiate contact with Best Practical in the future, you may be re-added to our database.Section 7: Additional Legal DisclosuresChildren: The Websites are not commercial websites or online services directed to children under 13 years of age and our content and other services are not written, intended, or designed for children under the age of 13. To ensure that BPS stays in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), we review the details of COPPA on a regular basis.Changes to this privacy policy: All versions of this privacy policy are dated with the effective date (the date on which the policy was posted to the Websites). We will only use the information we learn about you in the manner described in the Privacy Policy in effect when the information was collected from you. However, we reserve the right to change the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time by posting revisions to the Websites.Changes in corporate structure: If Best Practical is sold, merged or otherwise transferred to another entity, the personal information you have provided to the Websites may be transferred as part of that transaction. However, we will take steps to assure that any personal information is used in a manner consistent with the BPS privacy policy under which it was collected.Effect of Legal Obligations upon this Privacy Policy: Best Practical may disclose user information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) BPS’ rights or property, other BPS users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Best Practical may disclose user information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.Effect of Privacy Policy: This privacy policy is not intended to and does not create any contractual or legal rights in or on behalf of any party. As noted above, we may revise this privacy policy from time to time in our sole discretion.Terms of Service: Users of the Websites are also subject to Best Practical’s Terms of Service, found at: bestpractical.com/website-terms.Section 8: ContactIf you have any questions about the above Privacy Policy, please contact:Best Practical Solutions, LLCPO Box 441333Somerville, MA 02144contact@bestpractical.comTo download a copy of this document click here.
Email Address
Sign Up
Thank you! Follow us on Twitter to see what else we’re up to!
